[
    {
        "question": "Permeability is the inverse equivalent of which electrical term?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Voltage",
        "b": "Current",
        "c": "Resistance",
        "d": "Conductance",
        "answer": "Resistance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which electromagnetic device uses brushes and a commutator?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "A speaker",
        "b": "A dc generator",
        "c": "A relay",
        "d": "A solenoid",
        "answer": "A dc generator"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the flux density of a magnetic field whose flux is 3000 \u00b5Wb and cross-sectional area is 0.25 m^2?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "12,000 uT",
        "b": "83,330 T",
        "c": "0 T",
        "d": "More information is needed in order to find flux density.",
        "answer": "12,000 uT"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much flux is there in a magnetic field when its flux density is 5000 mu.gifT and its cross-sectional area is 300 mm2?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "16.67 mWb",
        "b": "5.0 uWb",
        "c": "3.0 mWb",
        "d": "1.5 uWb",
        "answer": "1.5 uWb"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the effects of moving a closed wire loop through a magnetic field?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "A voltage is induced in the wire.",
        "b": "A current is induced in the wire.",
        "c": "The polarity across the wire depends on the direction of motion.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hall effect\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "is a phenomenon with no practical applications",
        "b": "is used in various sensor applications",
        "c": "can develop potentials of thousands of volts",
        "d": "is the basis for solar cell operation",
        "answer": "is used in various sensor applications"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Series\" and \"parallel\" as applied to dc motors refer to\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the connection of the motor and controller",
        "b": "the connection of the field coil and armature windings",
        "c": "the connection of the brush and commutator",
        "d": "the connection of the motor batteries",
        "answer": "the connection of the field coil and armature windings"
    },
    {
        "question": "The component that produces power in an electromagnetic generator is called the\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "armature",
        "b": "field winding",
        "c": "commutator",
        "d": "brush",
        "answer": "armature"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the magnetomotive force in a 150-turn coil of wire with 2 A flowing through it?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "13.33 mAt",
        "b": "300 At",
        "c": "75 At",
        "d": "152 At",
        "answer": "300 At"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Hall effect sensor\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "exists only in theory",
        "b": "is a noncontacting magnetic sensor",
        "c": "can operate only a few times before failure",
        "d": "produces very large voltages",
        "answer": "is a noncontacting magnetic sensor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two values are plotted on a B-H curve graph?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Reluctance and flux density",
        "b": "Permeability and reluctance",
        "c": "Magnetizing force and permeability",
        "d": "Flux density and magnetizing force",
        "answer": "Flux density and magnetizing force"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which electromagnetic device has a flexible cone?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "A speaker",
        "b": "A dc generator",
        "c": "A relay",
        "d": "A solenoid",
        "answer": "A speaker"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the reluctance of a material that has a length of 0.045 m, a cross-sectional area of 0.015 m^2, and a permeability of 2500 \u00b5Wb\/At\u00b7m?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "833.33 \u00b5At\/Wb",
        "b": "0.27 At\/Wb",
        "c": "1200 At\/Wb",
        "d": "More information is needed in order to find the reluctance.",
        "answer": "1200 At\/Wb"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit of flux density is known as\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "magnetomotive force",
        "b": "a weber",
        "c": "a maxwell",
        "d": "a tesla",
        "answer": "a tesla"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you call the characteristic of a magnetic material whereby a change in magnetization lags the application of a magnetizing force?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Hysteresis",
        "b": "Induction",
        "c": "Retentivity",
        "d": "Reluctance",
        "answer": "Hysteresis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which electromagnetic device has a movable iron core called a plunger?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "A speaker",
        "b": "A dc generator",
        "c": "A relay",
        "d": "A solenoid",
        "answer": "A solenoid"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which electromagnetic device contains an armature?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "A speaker",
        "b": "A dc generator",
        "c": "A relay",
        "d": "A solenoid",
        "answer": "A dc generator"
    },
    {
        "question": "The polarity of induced voltage while a field is collapsing is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "independent of the force creating the field",
        "b": "opposite to the force creating the field",
        "c": "identical to the force creating the field",
        "d": "present only if the force is stationary",
        "answer": "opposite to the force creating the field"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit of magnetic flux density is the weber.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ability of a material to maintain a magnetized state (without the presence of a magnetizing force) is called retentivity.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Magnetic flux flows from the north pole to the south pole within the magnet.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hall voltage is the voltage created by a conductor moving through a magnetic field.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ability of a material to maintain a magnetized state (without the presence of a magnetizing force) is called hysteresis.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ferromagnetic materials have pre-existing magnetic fields.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit of magnetic flux is the weber.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "A voltage is induced across a conductor if it remains absolutely stationary within a magnetic field.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq7_1004_1.gifWhen the south poles of two bar magnets are brought close together, there will be a force of attraction.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq7_1002_1.gifA magnetic field is produced around a current-carrying conductor.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "A magnetic material such as iron can change the course of magnetic lines of force.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The induced emf of a conductor cutting flux lines is directly proportional to the rate of cutting.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The magnetic field, current through the Hall element, and Hall voltage are all at right angles to each other.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The operation of an electrical generator relies on electromagnetic induction.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq7_1001_1.gifWhen the current through a coil reverses direction, the magnetic field around the coil _____.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "does not change",
        "b": "disappears",
        "c": "increases in strength",
        "d": "reverses direction",
        "answer": "reverses direction"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flux density is ___ when the magnetic flux is 9 \u00b5Wb and the cross-sectional area of the magnetic field is 5 \u00d7 10^\u20133 m^2.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1800 \u00b5T",
        "b": "555.56 T",
        "c": "9 \u00b5T",
        "d": "5 \u00d7 10^\u20133 T",
        "answer": "1800 \u00b5T"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the magnetizing force has been removed, the ratio of the remaining magnetic flux to the saturated magnetic flux is called _____________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "saturation",
        "b": "retentivity",
        "c": "hysteresis",
        "d": "coercivity",
        "answer": "retentivity"
    },
    {
        "question": "You can determine the direction of the lines of force surrounding a conductor by using _____.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the right-hand rule",
        "b": "the left-hand rule",
        "c": "Lenz's law",
        "d": "Faraday's law",
        "answer": "the right-hand rule"
    },
    {
        "question": "A group of force lines going from the north pole to the south pole of a magnet is called the magnetic ___.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "retentivity",
        "b": "reluctance",
        "c": "hysteresis",
        "d": "flux",
        "answer": "flux"
    },
    {
        "question": "The induced voltage across a stationary conductor in a stationary magnetic field ___.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "equals 0 V",
        "b": "is usually very large",
        "c": "varies with time",
        "d": "depends on the strength of the magnetic field",
        "answer": "equals 0 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the speed at which a conductor is moved through a magnetic field is increased, the induced voltage will _____.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "not be affected",
        "b": "equal 0 V",
        "c": "decrease",
        "d": "increase",
        "answer": "increase"
    },
    {
        "question": "___ is the ability of a material to remain magnetized after removal of the magnetizing force.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Reluctance",
        "b": "Hysteresis",
        "c": "Retentivity",
        "d": "Induction",
        "answer": "Retentivity"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ferromagnetic materials have minute magnetic ___ created within their atomic structure by the orbital motion and spin of electrons.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "forces",
        "b": "flux lines",
        "c": "domains",
        "d": "tapes",
        "answer": "domains"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ___ is an electromagnetic device that contains a coil rotating on a jeweled bearing mount.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "permanent-magnet speaker",
        "b": "d'Arsonval movement",
        "c": "single-pole, double-throw relay",
        "d": "crankshaft position sensor",
        "answer": "d'Arsonval movement"
    }
]